resume-library.com 2018-09-03

# Terms & Conditions | Privacy Policy | Resume-Library.com

Resume-Library endeavours to ensure that the information that you submit to us remains private, and that it is used only for the purposes described below. We aim to provide a safe and secure experience for all of our users. We make every effort to comply with our obligations under the 1998 Data Protection Act. Additionally, we understand the importance of maintaining the confidentiality of your Resume and other information stored about you while using the site.

### Account and Resume information

When you register with Resume-Library your details, including your Resume, can be made available for searching, viewing over the Internet and downloading by any direct recruiter, employment consultant or other person or organisation who requests Resumes matching your profile to be sent to them. Resume-Library attempts to verify the identity and the nature of the business of such organisations however does not make any warranties as to their authenticity.

### Your personal information

When you create or upload your Resume with us, we will collect personal information from you, such as your name, contact details, and other details. Once you register with Resume-Library and accept our Terms & Conditions, you are not anonymous to us. We may use information that you provide to alert you to our own products and services. We may contact you regarding site changes or changes to the Resume-Library products or services that you use.

### Disclosure of personal information

When you register, we store some information about you in your account, but it is protected by your password and may only be accessed by you. It does not form part of our candidate database and cannot be searched or accessed by Resume-Library customers. You can delete your account at any time.

If you choose to create a profile and upload a Resume to our database, we rely on you to ensure that your details are kept up to date. You should update your CV at least every six months, particularly if your contact details have changed.

Please note that Resume-Library reserves the right to remove from our database, Resumes which include any content that we consider to be illegal or offensive.

We do not disclose information about your individual visits to the Resume-Library site, or personal information that you provide, such as your name and personal contact details unless you have given us your permission or we believe that the law requires it. N.B. that by registering with Resume-Library you are granting us permission to disclose this information. We may record and share aggregated information with our clients. Additionally, if you input your information on a co-branded registration page or job application page, eg a Resume-Library client-company registration page then the information that you give becomes the property of both Resume-Library and the client. Resume-Library is not responsible for the information that the client receives.

Resume-Library will also use the aggregate data to identify employment trends across different industries, such as salary averages. This information will not be capable of being linked to any personally identifying information about users.

**PLEASE NOTE:** Your current employer may be a customer of Resume-Library, or a client of one of our customers. Resume-Library cannot restrict the customers who access profiles on our database and cannot be held responsible for any eventuality.

### Information collection and use

Like many websites, we routinely capture your IP address information to determine your location. This helps us work out whether you are visiting the site from within the UK, EU or rest of the world, and means we can show you content that's specific to your location and ask the right questions about your eligibility to work in the specific country you are wishing to work in, should you wish to apply for a job on Resume-Library. Resume-Library automatically receives and records information on our web server logs from your browser including your IP address. Resume-Library records IP addresses for anonymous statistical purposes, administration of our website and servers, and to improve our services.

An IP address, or 'internet protocol address', is a unique identifying number given to every device connected to the internet. Like a car license plate, an IP address is a special serial number used for identification.

Information may be gathered from your registration form and your use of our website through "cookies". The information gathered may be used by Resume-Library internally, for purposes relating to your use of the website and for marketing activities, and may be passed to carefully selected third parties to use for marketing activities. If you subsequently decide you no longer wish to receive direct marketing/information from Resume-Library or no longer wish us to pass your information to third parties you should notify us using the Contact page of our website or delete your Resume.

Resume-Library may set and access cookies on your computer. You can choose whether or not to accept cookies, however, if you do not accept Resume-Library cookies, some of our services may not be available to you. This policy does not apply to companies that Resume-Library does not own or control, or to people that Resume-Library does not employ.

Notwithstanding any other provision, we may also engage a data provider who may collect weblog data from you (including IP address and information about your browser or operating system), or place or recognize a unique cookie on your browser to enable you to receive customized ads or content. These cookies contain no personally identifiable information. The cookies may reflect de-identified demographic or other data linked to data you voluntarily have submitted to us, e.g., your email address, that we may share with a data provider solely in hashed, non-human readable form.

### Statistical information

Resume-Library gathers general information about users, for example, what services users access the most and which areas of the Resume-Library site are most frequently visited, the number of Resumes on the database, or the number of visitors to the site and for other lawful purposes. Such data is used in the aggregate to help us to understand how the Resume-Library site is used. We gather this information so that we can continue to improve and develop our services to benefit our users. We may make this aggregated information available to users of the Resume-Library site, to our clients, advertisers, suppliers and other reputable third parties. These statistics are anonymous and contain no personal information and cannot be used to gather such information.

### Security

The site is protected against unauthorised access using the latest security devices and 'firewalls'.

Similar to the spam you receive in your personal email inbox, fraudsters have started creating false job offers in an attempt to gather personal details. We consistently monitor job postings on the site and we are committed to ensuring that jobs listed on Resume-Library.com are legitimate and comply with our terms & conditions.

At no point during the application process with Resume-Library should you be asked to complete any monetary transactions or provide personal information beyond your resume.

If you notice anything suspicious, we advise you to email us on [help@resume-library.com](mailto:help@resume-library.com) and stop communication with the recruiter or employer. For more information on how to spot scam emails, take a look at this blog [post](https://www.resume-library.com/career-advice/getting-started/job-scam-warning-signs-report-one/).

### Other ways of ensuring your privacy:

You may amend your personal details at any time. These options are available when you login to our website.

You may unsubscribe from any employment or promotional information that we may send to you by in any of the following ways:

  * Using the unsubscribe function at the bottom of the email

  * Amending your account details by logging in to our website

  * Contacting us on the Contact page of our website

### Resume-Library Cookie Policy

Resume-Library uses browser cookies; this means our webservers put small files (the 'cookies') onto your computer to collect information as you use the website. What the cookies contain varies depending on the features they are being used for. Cookies enable Resume-Library to monitor traffic, remember users and their preferences and to provide features to users across multiple web servers.

We use third-party advertising companies to serve ads when you visit our website. These companies may use information (not including your name, address, email address or telephone number) about your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice and to know your options for not having this information used by these companies, [click here](http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp).

### Google Analytics

Resume-Library uses Google Analytics to help analyze how users use the site. The tool uses "cookies", which are text files placed on your computer, to collect standard Internet log information and visitor behavior information in an anonymous form. The information generated by the cookie about your use of the website (including IP address) is transmitted to Google. This information is then used to evaluate visitor's use of the website and to compile statistical reports on website activity for Resume-Library.

We will never (and will not allow any third party to) use the statistical analytics tool to track or to collect any Personally Identifiable Information (PII) of visitors to our site. Google will not associate your IP address with any other data held by Google. Neither we nor Google will link, or seek to link, an IP address with the identity of a computer user. We will not associate any data gathered from this site with any Personally Identifiable Information from any source, unless you explicitly submit that information via a fill-in form on our website.

You may choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically default to accept them, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies. If you reject cookies by changing your browser settings then be aware that this may disable some of the functionality on our website.

Any further queries should be directed through our contact form.

You can remove any of the information that Resume-Library stores about you, at any time, by logging in to your Resume-Library account and choosing to delete the account.
